Sam Mans

Email: smans.tech@gmail.com
My Portfolio | GitHub | Linkedin

About Me

A Software Engineer with experience supporting enterprise, mobile, and web-based applications

Skills and Tools

Web Development

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Node, NgRx, Jasmine/Karma, SCSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, MongoDB, GIT

Services

GitHub, BitBucket, AWS EC2, CloudWatch, Jenkins CI/CD, Google Analytics, Mailchimp

Software

VSCode, Intellij, SourceTree, PgAdmin, SQLite, Spring Tool Suite, Redux Devtools, Postman

Workflow

JIRA, Slack, Basecamp, Microsoft Teams, Zoom, Agile Development

Relevant Work Experience

Software Engineer, Depository Trust & Clearing Corporation

(November 2019 to Present)

- Working as part of the DTCC Institutional Trade Processing unit's application development team
- Contributing to DTCC's shared component and capability libraries built with Angular 9
- Leading weekly UI cross-team meetings to coordinate efforts and updates to shared libraries
- Working with backend engineers to define requirements and coordinate changes to services and APIs
- Performing technical interviews, assisting newly onboarded engineers, and mentoring junior staff

Angular 9 | NgRx | Jasmine/Karma | Bitbucket | JIRA | Jenkins CI/ CD | CloudWatch | EC2 | Maven

Web Developer, Syyrup - RBKJ

(September 2017 to October 2019)

- Working in web development and marketing for <u>Svyrup</u>, a positive news application
- Working with the lead developer and product team to improve the application, create content, measure performance, design promotional material, and manage social media activity
- Coordinating updates to the application and social media efforts with remote team members

Angular 2+ | Ionic | Firebase | GitHub | Analytics | Social Media | Digital Marketing

Web Migration and Production Assistant, National Association of Realtors (August 2017 - December 2017)

- Working as part of NAR's web production and migration team transitioning old site content to the new Drupal 7 website <u>nar.realtor</u>
- Working with departments countrywide to publish digital content, troubleshooting site-wide issues, attending daily stand-up meetings, and testing site changes prior to release

Drupal | Jira | HTML/CSS | JavaScript | Quality Assurance | Agile

Education, Certifications and Coursework

B.S.B.A Marketing | Suffolk University, Boston, MA

- Concentration in Marketing and Information Systems Management

A+ Certification | COMPTIA

- Computer technician certification for computer installation, troubleshooting, and support